Muhammed Esat Ozen

Software Developer

Winchester, MA (203) 278-6572

ozenesat@gmail.com

Portfolio ↗, GitHub ↗, LinkedIn ↗

(Authorized to work in the US for any employer)

Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React-Native, Redux, Next.js, Stencil, Node.js, Python, Adobe DTM, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, Postman, REST, JSON, Git/GitHub/Gitlab, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Material-Ul, Ubuntu, Agile, Kanban.

Experience

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

CVS Health, Woonsocket, RI- Software Engineer II

- Building, testing, and releasing new easy onboarding and account management experiences in TypeScript with NextJs and React Hooks for CVS.com.
- Developing dynamic, reusable components with Stencil, React, RESTful Architecture.
- Partnering with the product and design team to develop and design the most efficient and smoothest flows for the best user experience.
- Maintaining and contributing to Flagship, an open-source code platform for developing e-commerce solutions across Web, iOS and Android using React Native.

JAN 2021 - OCT 2021

CVS Health, Woonsocket, RI- Software Engineer

- Built new e-commerce pages and COVID-19 vaccination experiences in React Native and Redux which is used by more than ten thousand users per day.
- Designed and lead the development of building the new CarePass flow with NextJs, Stencil.
- Created user interfaces with React to build reusable functional components and employed React Hooks for better state management.
- Integrated and analyzed the Adobe Dynamic Tagging to improve performance and UX.

MAY 2020 - DEC 2020

Liana Networks, Beaverton, OR - Front-end Developer

- Designed, implemented and tested the application from scratch with Next.Js & React.
- Implemented OAuth authorization to access Google APIs into the React app with JWT.
- Integrated YouTube Data API that hits ~10 K req. per day for the live stream and live chat.
- Developed the start & control live broadcast functionality with YouTube Live Streaming API.
- Built and consumed Restful APIs in coordination with 3rd Party APIs & SDKs and backend.

MAY 2019 - FEB 2020

Ace It Education, Boston, MA - Web Developer

- Built and maintained two websites for the company's DBAs with WordPress.
- Managed e-mail accounts with G-Suite and e-mail campaigns with MailChimp.
- Provided technical support for the weekly events and classes of the company.
- Created social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

The Fix, Farmington, CT – Project Manager

- Efficiently managed a yearly budget of ~\$1 million and increased the profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services tailored to customer needs.

MAY 2013 - APR 2016

Zaman Media Group, Ankara, Turkey – Correspondent

• Worked with editors and senior correspondents as a team to cover all of the latest political news from the Capitol. Reported on judicial news from the courts.

Education

FEB 2020 - MAY 2020

General Assembly, Boston, MA - Software Engineering Immersive

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- Built client-side applications with responsive behavior using React with third-party APIs.
- Developed 4 full-stack web applications in four days sprints independently and collaboratively while practicing Agile methodology. Utilized Git for version control.

SEP 2008 - JUN 2012

Middle East Technical University – Bachelor of Science, Mathematics

Abstract Algebra, Combinatorics, Cryptography, Discrete Mathematics, Intro to C, Number Theory *Honors*; Proudly served as elected President of the Student Council for two years.

Summary

With a quantitative academic background and startup experience, able to master new skills quickly. Enjoys breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking in transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Believes in team play and never-ending personal growth. Experienced in diverse work areas in three different countries as a highly adaptive world citizen.